Guide to the Bidwell Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Personal Papers of Other Bidwell and Related Families, 1750-1952; 1850-1915; Series III
  - Bidwell Family, Individual Members
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (Writings)
      - "A Case of Acute Dissipation", 1875 July (Box 13, Folder 447, Reel 8U)
      - "Havana Glen", 1875 August 13 (Box 13, Folder 448, Reel 8U)
      - Leaflets for the Scrapbook No. 7; No. 8, 1875 September (Box 13, Folder 449, Reel 8U)
      - "A Venerable Relic" re: the Pharmacaopoeia Meadiana, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 450, Reel 8U)
      - Review of Froude's History of England, 1877 August (Box 13, Folder 451, Reel 8U)
      - "The Great Patagonian Brainmaker", Undated (Box 13, Folder 452, Reel 8U)
      - Poem with illustrations, Undated (Box 13, Folder 453, Reel 8U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (Notebooks)
      - Higglegy Piggledy, 1855-1877 (Box 13, Folder 454, Reel 8U)
      - Notebook II, including puzzles, magic, games, anecdotes songs, American authors, and other miscellaneous subjects, 1857 February (Box 13, Folder 455, Reel 8U)
      - Notebook III, including maps, knots, painting, notes on physical science, novels and history, and other subjects, 1858 (Box 13, Folder 456, Reel 8U)
      - Index to notebooks, [1858?] (Box 13, Folder 457, Reel 8U)
      - Book of first names with meanings, 1863 (Box 13, Folder 458, Reel 8U)
      - Memoranda of letters written by M. S. Bidwell, Jr., continued by Alice C. Bidwell, 1876-1882 (Box 13, Folder 459, Reel 8U)
      - Jewish Account of the Trial of Jesus, translated from Book IV, Ch. III of Histoire des Institutions de Moise et du Peuple Hébreu by Joseph Salvador (Box 13, Folder 460, Reel 8U)
      - The monogram album, Undated (Box 13, Folder 461, Reel 8U)
      - Pharmacist's notebook, with recipes and ingredients (index included), Undated (Box 13, Folder 462, Reel 8U)
      - "Scientific Index, or Memoranda from Reading and Observation", Undated (Box 13, Folder 463, Reel 8U)
      - Family scrapbook (Box 13, Folder 464, Reel 8U)
      - "Seals, Wafers, etc.", Undated (Box 13, Folder 465, Reel 8U)
      - "Selections in Prose and Verse", Undated (Box 13, Folder 466, Reel 8U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (Legal Papers) Clippings and Photos
      - Certificate of marriage, Marshall S. Bidwell, Jr. and Alice Cecilia Bidwell, 1866 January 14 (Box 15, Folder 467, Reel 8U)
      - Last will and testament of Marshall S. Bidwell, Jr., 1874 February (Box 15, Folder 468, Reel 8U)
      - Clippings: "Zoological," "American Pharmaceutical Association" [empty] (Box 15, Folder 469, Reel 8U)
        See:box 13, folder 464
      - Clippings re: M. S. Bidwell, Jr., 1877, 1933, undated (Box 15, Folder 470, Reel 8U)
      - Portraits of Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (Box 15, Folder 471, Reel 8U)
      - Portraits of the class of 1856, Columbia College (Box 15, Folder 472, Reel 9U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell (1893-1919)
      - Letters to "Aunt Alice" (2), 1905-1906 (Box 15, Folder 473, Reel 9U)
      - Organ concerts and biographical sketch, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 474, Reel 9U)
    - Mary Gray Bidwell (1764-1808)
      - Edwards, T. (Box 14, Folder 475, Reel 9U)
      - Death of Mrs. Barnabas Bidwell, obituary and soliloquy, 1808 (Box 15, Folder 476, Reel 9U)
      - Sermon at the funeral of Mrs. Mary Gray Bidwell, 1808 February 6 (Box 15, Folder 477, Reel 9U)
    - Mary Sabra Bidwell (1823-1889)
      - Abbott, Jacob (2), 1878-1879 (Box 15, Folder 478, Reel 9U)
      - Abbott, Jacob (1), 1879 (Box 15, Folder 479, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Clara W. (1), 1834 (Box 15, Folder 480, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (4), 1855-1862 (Box 15, Folder 481, Reel 9U)
      - Merit citation from a teacher, 1828 (Box 15, Folder 482, Reel 9U)
      - Last will and testament, 1866 (Box 15, Folder 483, Reel 9U)
    - Meliscent Dench Bidwell (1764-1860)
      - Notebook and family record, 1837-1859 (Box 15, Folder 484, Reel 9U)
    - Orlando Curtis Bidwell (1862-19?)
      - Clippings (Box 15, Folder 485, Reel 9U)
    - Sarah Gray Bidwell (1796-1864)
      - Bidwell, Mary Gray (5), 1806-1807 (Box 16, Folder 486, Reel 9U)
    - Sophia Bidwell (1829-1897)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (1), 1854 (Box 16, Folder 487, Reel 9U)
    - Walter Davidson Bidwell (1860-1896)
      - Photographs of Walter D. Bidwell (Box 16, Folder 488, Reel 9U)
    - Mary Gray Bidwell Cone (1831-19?)
      - Bidwell, Clara Emily (3), 1907-1908 (Box 16, Folder 489, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Emmeline M. (1), 1863 (Box 16, Folder 490, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Henrietta W. (2), 1863 (Box 16, Folder 491, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Dench; Bidwell, Emmeline M. (1), 1862 (Box 16, Folder 492, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Milla (1), 1863 (Box 16, Folder 493, Reel 9U)
      - Fitch, Sarah A. (1), 1896 (Box 16, Folder 494, Reel 9U)
      - Karrick, Ella Cecelia Bidwell (1), 1863 (Box 16, Folder 495, Reel 9U)
      - Cone family correspondence (3), 1859, 1922, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 495a, Reel 9U)
      - Cone family papers (6), 1855-1894 (Box 16, Folder 495b, Reel 9U)
      - "The Necessity for a Constant Readiness for Death", 1766 May 25 (Box 16, Folder 496, Reel 9U)
    - Sarah Spring Gray
      - Bidwell, Mary Gray (1), 1798 (Box 16, Folder 497, Reel 9U)
      - Gray, James (1), 1780 (Box 16, Folder 498, Reel 9U)
    - Alice Sophia Orton (1853-19?)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (2) (Box 16, Folder 499, Reel 9U)
      - Correspondence from Janet and Frances Warren, daughters of Clara L. Bidwell Warren (15), 1909-1912 (Box 16, Folder 500, Reel 9U)
    - Azariah Orton (1761-1854)
      - Appraisal of real estate of Azariah Orton (incomplete), Undated (Box 16, Folder 501, Reel 9U)
    - Beulah C. Orton (1846-1924)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (1), Undated (Box 16, Folder 502, Reel 9U)
    - John Jackson Orton (1842-1919)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (1), 1902 (Box 16, Folder 503, Reel 9U)
      - Brown, Sarah Orton (1), Undated (Box 16, Folder 504, Reel 9U)
      - Jackson, James H. [empty], 1891-1894 (Box 16, Folder 505, Reel 9U)
        See:box 5, folder 235
      - Letter of J. J. Orton to a sister (1), 1910 (Box 16, Folder 506, Reel 9U)
    - Thomas Bidwell Orton (1844-1867)
      - Letters of Thomas Bidwell Orton to his family re: service, in the Union Army (6), 1862-1863 (Box 16, Folder 507, Reel 9U)
      - Certificates of military service in the Union Army, 1862, 1864 (Box 16, Folder 508, Reel 9U)
    - Alice Bidwell Warren (1899-19?)
      - Correspondence of Alice B. Warren (7), 1926, 1938, undated (Box 16, Folder 509, Reel 9U)
      - Francis Scott Keys Memorial Association [empty] (Box 16, Folder 510, Reel 9U)
        - Oversize, 1908 (Box 19, Reel 9U)
    - Charles Herbert Warren
      - Hancy, Edward J., correspondence re: Clara E. Bidwell's estate (14), 1912-1913 (Box 16, Folder 511, Reel 9U)
      - Rathburn, Henry V., Stockbridge Monumental Works re: tombstone for Clara E. Bidwell (6), 1912 (Box 16, Folder 512, Reel 9U)
      - Correspondence re: business at Charles Scribner's Sons (6), 1919-1926 (Box 16, Folder 513, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Agnes H. (1), 1891 (Box 16, Folder 514, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Charles (3), 1880, 1897 (Box 16, Folder 515, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Frederick (circa 12), 1891-1895 (Box 16, Folder 516, Reel 9U)
      - Scribner Christmas Dinner, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 517, Reel 9U)
      - Three portraits of Charles H. Warren and the C. H. Warren family (Box 16, Folder 518, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (16), 1902-1906, undated (Box 16, Folder 519, Reel 9U)
      - Warren announcements of marriage and birth, family record (Box 16, Folder 520, Reel 9U)
      - Photos of Alice, Janet, and Frances Warren, daughters of C. H. W. and Clara Bidwell (Box 16, Folder 521, Reel 9U)
      - Family photos at Monterey, Massachusetts, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 522, Reel 9U)
      - Sons of the American Revolution certificate, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 523, Reel 9U)
    - Clara Luna Bidwell Warren (1871-19?)
      - Allen, Emma F. (1), Undated (Box 16, Folder 524, Reel 9U)
      - Beecher, Thomas. K. (1), 1898 (Box 16, Folder 525, Reel 9U)
      - Benjamin, Alice M. (1), 1888 (Box 16, Folder 526, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, A. (4), 1890-1894 (Box 16, Folder 527, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (2), 1898, undated (Box 16, Folder 528, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Jacob Abbott (1), 1882 (Box 16, Folder 529, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (4), 1874, 1877 (Box 16, Folder 530, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Mary S. and Clara E. (1), 1879 (Box 16, Folder 531, Reel 9U)
      - Bidwell, Orlando Curtis [empty], 1926 (Box 16, Folder 532, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Agnes H. (1), 1897 (Box 16, Folder 533, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Charles Herbert (circa 35), 1895-1898, undated (Box 16, Folder 534, Reel 9U)
      - Warren, Frederick (1), 1897 (Box 16, Folder 535, Reel 9U)
      - Welsh, Dr. William H., Rotch, Dr. T. M. (3), 1903 (Box 16, Folder 536, Reel 9U)
      - Young, Florence (1), 1913 (Box 16, Folder 537, Reel 9U)
      - Fragments of letters by Clara Bidwell Warren (2), 1908 (Box 16, Folder 538, Reel 9U)
      - "Personal Items," events in her life, 1882-1913 (Box 17, Folder 539, Reel 9U)
      - Diploma from Mount Holyoke College [empty] (Box 17, Folder 540, Reel 9U)
        - Oversize, 1892 (Box 19, Reel 9U)
      - Pratt Institute certificate, 1895 (Box 17, Folder 541, Reel 9U)
      - Marriage certificate [empty] (Box 17, Folder 542, Reel 9U)
        - Oversize, 1898 (Box 19, Reel 9U)
      - Certificate of appreciation, Selective Service Board, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 543, Reel 9U)
      - Estimate of labor and materials for construction of a house; payment of architect, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 544, Reel 9U)
        - Oversize, 1913 March 28 (Box 19, Reel 9U)
      - Ancestral register of Clara Luna Bidwell Warren [empty] (Box 17, Folder 545, Reel 9U)
        - Oversize (Box 19, Reel 9U)
      - Clippings re: Clara L. B. Warren (Box 17, Folder 546, Reel 9U)
      - Two portraits of Clara Warren with daughter Janet and with Marion Howard (Box 17, Folder 547, Reel 9U)
    - William W. Welsh, M.D. (1818-1892)
      - Bidwell, Louisa M. (1), 1838 (Box 17, Folder 548, Reel 9U)
  - Correspondence, Writings, and Photographs of Others
    - Julia Beecher and R. S. Beecher to Mrs. Mary Beecher (1), 1834 (Box 17, Folder 549, Reel 9U)
    - Laugrin, Léon to A. Géran, an aide of General Bragg, asking a favor for a friend, Mr. Levy (1), 1861 April 29 (Box 17, Folder 550, Reel 9U)
    - Homer Morgan to Mr. Snelling re: lots in New York (1), 1853 May 19 (Box 17, Folder 551, Reel 9U)
    - Walter Anonym (pseudonym) to unidentified, St. Valentine's Day (1), 1859 (Box 17, Folder 552, Reel 9U)
    - "The Elephant," by Mrs. T. K. Beecher (Box 17, Folder 553, Reel 9U)
      See also: box 13, folder 464
    - "Visits to the Italian Battle Fields of Napoleon. Marengo.", Circa 1850 (Box 17, Folder 554, Reel 9U)
      The MS. is signed "Douglass," possibly Douglass Prentiss, a friend and business associate of Marshall S. Bidwell.
    - Photo of Lyman Abbott (Box 17, Folder 555, Reel 9U)
    - Photo of the Beecher homestead, Barkhawsted Hollow, Connecticut (Box 17, Folder 556, Reel 9U)
    - Photo of Julia L. Beecher Hart, taken by Mary W. Bidwell, 1887 (Box 17, Folder 557, Reel 9U)
    - Photographs of Reverend Thomas K. Beecher and of memorial statue (Box 17, Folder 558, Reel 9U)